<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pagedata>
	<title>How to submit data</title>
	<menutitle>How to submit data</menutitle>
	<synopsis><![CDATA[]]></synopsis>
	<lang>en</lang>
	<content><![CDATA[
<p align="right"><font color="#336666" face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="4"><b>Data 
	depositing procedure</b></font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">The depositing procedure 
	is very important, both for clearly understanding the data owners' requests and for 
	quickly and accurately integrating the data sets in our archive.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">The information below 
	guide you through the depositing procedure steps, how the data should be prepared for 
	depositing, how the data reach RODA and what happen to them afterwards. If you have any 
	questions, please <a href="template.php?url=4">contact</a> us for further explanations.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">In order for the data set 	
	to be fully usable, any researcher or interested person will need additional information. 
	The data set is useful to no one unless provided with a well-structured documentation. 
	With a view to depositing data, please:</font></p>

<div align="justify"><ul><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
	<li>fill in the <a href="http://www.roda.ro/documente/Depunere.pdf">Depositing form</a> 
		(giving details about the dataset);</li>
	<li>fill in and the sign the <a href="http://www.roda.ro/documente/Licenta.pdf">License 
		agreement</a>, mentioning the conditions and restrictions regarding the dissemination 
		of data;</li>
	<li>send these documents to us, with the data set and the related documentation.</li>
</font></ul></div>

<p align="justify"><b><font color="#FF0000" face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">Please 
	prepare:</font></b></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
	- a copy of the dataset;<br>
	- a copy of the questionnaire, if possible bearing the name of the variables - they 
		should be the identical with the database variables;<br>
	- detailes about sampling data collection methods;<br>
	- a copy of the instructions to the field operators;<br>
	- information on variables and their values, coding and classification schemes used;<br>
	- information on the newly-created variables;<br>
	- details on the weighting procedures (if any) and weighting variables.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">We can use databases created 
	in Access, Excel, SPSS, SAS, STATA, as well as the information on the data set documentation 
	in Word, RTF, Acrobat PDF, both on electronic and printed format, if they can be scanned.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">The current storage media we 
	can use are floppy disks, CDs and electronic transfer by FTP.</font></p>
	
	]]></content>
	<cms_layout>roda-main-en</cms_layout>
	<pagetype>content</pagetype>
	<cacheable>3600</cacheable>
	<searchable>true</searchable>	
	<default_page>0</default_page>
	<external_redirect></external_redirect>
	<internal_redirect></internal_redirect>
	<navigable>true</navigable>
	<published>true</published>
	<target></target>
	<visible>true</visible>
</pagedata>