<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pagedata>
	<title>RODA</title>
	<menutitle>RODA</menutitle>
	<url>home</url>
	<synopsis><![CDATA[RODA is the national Romanian institution specialised in archiving electronic data collections obtained by social research.]]></synopsis>
	<lang>en</lang>
	<content><![CDATA[
<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
RODA is the national Romanian institution specialised in archiving electronic data collections obtained by social research.
</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
The archive contains data collections accessible for the academic community and the interested public, 
for secondary and comparative analysis, under certain
<a href="[[Code: PageLinkbyUrl('access-levels')]]">access conditions</a> 
ranging from free access to some level of restriction imposed by owners.
</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
The main goal of the data archive is to preserve these data indefinitely, and to serve
as an intermediary between the data owners and data users.
</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
RODA is integrated into a global archive network, being affiliated since February 2002 to 
<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cessda.org">CESSDA</a> (Council of European Social Science Data Archives) and since December 2002 to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ifdo.org/">IFDO</a> 
(International Federation of Data Organisations). By these links, international data exchanges are enabled; 
through RODA, users have access to national and international datasets from other European data archives.
</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
In december 2013, CESSDA has become an ERIC - European Research Infrastructure Consortium, a research entity
considered a pan-European priority, located in Bergen, Norway. Since our IT system has been recently upgraded,
RODA is prepared to inter-operate with this new institution.
</font></p>


<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
RODA is now organised an institutional consortium, governed by the University of Bucharest, the National Institute
of Statistics and the Institute for Quality of Life Research of the Romanian Academy of Sciences.
</font></p>	]]></content>
	<cms_layout>new-roda-home-en</cms_layout>
	<pagetype>content</pagetype>
	<cacheable>3600</cacheable>
	<searchable>true</searchable>		
	<default_page>0</default_page>
	<sequence>1</sequence>
	<external_redirect></external_redirect>
	<internal_redirect></internal_redirect>
	<navigable>true</navigable>
	<published>true</published>
	<target></target>
	<visible>true</visible>
	<sequence>1</sequence>
</pagedata>