<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pagedata>
	<title>Best practices</title>
	<menutitle>Best practices</menutitle>
	<synopsis><![CDATA[]]></synopsis>
	<lang>en</lang>
	<content><![CDATA[
<p align="right"><font color="#336666" face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="4"><b>Guide 
	to good practice in data documentation</b></font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">Good data documentation 
	is of a crucial importance both for preserving data for the future use, and for secondary 
	research. Any person working with a dataset needs to have all the information available 
	in order to produce relevant tables and draw consistent conclusions.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">For a well documented 
	dataset, the data producers should prepare:</font></p>

<div align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2"><ul>
	<li>The dataset: cleaned, with both the variables and their values labelled </li>
 	<li>The questionnaire (in original, both printed and electronic versions)</li>
	<li>Information about the research that yielded the dataset</li>
</ul></font></div>

<p align="justify"><font color="#FF0000" face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
	<b>Dataset</b></font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">The important factors 
	for the users of a dataset are the clarity, variables in the database in conformity 
	with the questions in the questionnaire and the extent to which the variables are 
	‘self explained’. There are many cases when potentially valuable variables can no longer 
	be used due to the lack of information about their value (e.g. for open ended questions). 
	After a while, such information will be permanently lost. Information regarding the 
	dataset's structure should be prepared, with a complete list of all variables and their 
	description, includind details on the coding process and the classifications used.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">Equally useful is the 
	information related newly computed variables. The computation algorithm should be explained, 
	if possible together with the formula that has been used (if any).</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font color="#FF0000" face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
	<b>Questionnaire</b></font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">Although some variables 
	are self-explanatory, there are many cases when reading the corresponding question in the 
	questionnaire helps to a better understanding.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">In case of quite recent 
	researches for which there are questionnaire electronic forms, preparing such forms in a 
	recent Microsoft Word version, with the original page layout, would be of much help. The 
	electronic version should preferably contain diacritical marks, too.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">For the less recent studies,
	we can scan a physical copy of the questionnaire ant try to transform it into a text 
	using a optical character recognition program.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font color="#FF0000" face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">
	<b>Information about the research</b></font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">Such information is 
	essential for users; the data set and its contents cannot be fully understood unless 
	having prepared this information.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">For each dataset, RODA 
	fills in a study description form. This form is used by all major data archives in  
	the world and it is based on the <a href="http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI/">DDI</a>  
	(Data Documentation Initiative) structure, a project promoted by 
	<a href="http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/">ICPSR</a>, Michigan SUA.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">It is necessary to prepare 
	detailed information on the data gathering methods and instructions for the field 
	operators, sampling procedures and weighting procedures.</font></p>

<p align="justify"><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif" size="2">The interested persons
	can consult our <a target="_blank" href="/static/docs/en/DepositForm.pdf">Depositing form</a> in order to fill in the
	relevant information.</font></p>	]]></content>
	<cms_layout>new-roda-main-en</cms_layout>
	<pagetype>content</pagetype>
	<cacheable>3600</cacheable>
	<searchable>true</searchable>	
	<default_page>0</default_page>
	<external_redirect></external_redirect>
	<internal_redirect></internal_redirect>
	<navigable>true</navigable>
	<published>true</published>
	<target></target>
	<visible>true</visible>
	<sequence>1</sequence>
</pagedata>